John Windmuller Papers /4224
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
John Windmuller Papers
1950-1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Windmuller, John P.
/4224
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
8055325
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 13, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 04, 2016
Biographical / Historical
John P. Windmuller (December 4, 1923 December 2, 2003) was Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of the University of Illinois (BA, 1948) and Cornell University's ILR School (PhD, 1951), Windmuller joined the Cornell University faculty in 1951. He was appointed the Martin P. Catherwood Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations in 1983. He was named professor emeritus in 1987.
An expert in the study of international and comparative labor relations, Windmuller authored many books and reports on the topic, among them Collective Bargaining in Industrial Market Economies: A Reappraisal (ILO, 1987) and Labor Relations in the Netherlands (Ithaca: Cornell, 1969). With Alan Gladstone, he edited Employer Associations and Industrial Relations: A Comparative Study (New York: Oxford, 1984).
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor John Windmuller: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18116
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4146: John Windmuller Additional Papers
Windmuller, John P.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8055325
- ILR 430II folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ILR 430II folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ILR 500 folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ILR 500 folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- ILR 500 folder 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- ILR 430I folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- ILR 430I folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- ILR 430I folder 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- ILR 500 outlines & exams, Fall 1958 Spring 1959 folder 1, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- ILR 500 folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- ILR 530I folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- ILR 530I folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- ILR 530I folder 3 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- ILR 530II folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- ILR 530II folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- ILR 530II folder 3 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- ILR 581I folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- ILR 581I folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- ILR 581 folder 3 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- ILR 531II folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- ILR 531II folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- ILR 531II folder 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- ILR 630 folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- ILR 630 folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- ILR 630 folder 3 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 50th Anniversary of ILR School (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Foreign Unions, 1964-1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- ICEF, 1974-1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Foreign Unions, 1965-1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- ETUC, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- ETUC, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miners International Federation, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- ITS, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Jay Lovestone, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- IFBWW, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Union Concentration Analysis, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- ICFTU Ms., 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- IGF, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- IFPAAW/IUF, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- ISETU-FIET, 1982-1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- FIET, 1986-1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- General International Files (Box 3, Folder 1)
- ICA-FOA-NSA-ECA (Box 3, Folder 2)
- German Program 1/2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- German Program 2/2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Institute of Internal ILR, 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- International Labor Conference, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Scope and Contents
  October 1958
- Chilean Trade Union Leader Seminar (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Guillen, Carlos (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Andres Bello University (Venezuela) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Hillman Foundation (Box 3, Folder 10)
- International Programs - Financial (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Latin America (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Latin America, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Latin America - Dean's file (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Latin American Institute (Dean's Files) (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Mexico City - Latin Education Committee (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Middle East Program (McConnell File) (Box 3, Folder 17)
- International Labor Relations Grant (Box 3, Folder 18)
- San Jacinto Fund (O'Connor) (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Turkish Project Report by Corvini (Box 3, Folder 20)
- University Latin America Committee (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Reports of Division Directors, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Reports of Division Directors, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Appendix to Reports of Division Directors, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Reports of Division Directors, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- AID - Appointment & Clearance Forms (Box 4, Folder 1)
- AID - Contract Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 2)
- AID - Correspondence w/ AID (Box 4, Folder 3)
- AID - Equipment (Box 4, Folder 4)
- AID - Extension Program (Box 4, Folder 5)
- AID - Foundation Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 6)
- AID - Beryl Frank (Box 4, Folder 7)
- AID - Lois Gray (Box 4, Folder 8)
- AID - Correspondence w/ Gregory (Box 4, Folder 9)
- AID - Job Applications & Inquiries (Box 4, Folder 10)
- AID - Henry Landsberger, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  January 1, 1964
- AID - Henry Landsberger, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  November 1, 1962
- AID - Henry Landsberger, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  February 12, 1961 to October 31, 1962
- AID - Library, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- AID - Library Program (Box 4, Folder 15)
- AID - Local Seminars (Box 4, Folder 16)
- AID - Correspondence w/ McCarthy (Box 4, Folder 17)
- AID - Medical Examinations (Box 4, Folder 18)
- AID - Minutes of Insora Meetings (Box 4, Folder 19)
- AID - Misc. & Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 20)
- AID - Correspondence w/ Morris, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- AID - Correspondence w/ Morris, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- AID - Correspondence w/ Morris, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- AID - Monthly Reports on Participants (Box 4, Folder 24)
- AID - Participant Allowances (Box 4, Folder 25)
- AID - Participants Field Trips (Box 4, Folder 26)
- AID - Participant Forms A-H (Box 4, Folder 27)
- AID - Participant Forms I-Z (Box 4, Folder 28)
- AID - Participant Studies, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- AID - Participant Students (Box 5, Folder 2)
- AID - Participants' Supplementary Fund (Box 5, Folder 3)
- AID - Peterson (Box 5, Folder 4)
- AID - Program Announcements (Box 5, Folder 5)
- AID - Program Reports (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Appendix (Box 5, Folder 7)
- AID - Research Program (Box 5, Folder 8)
- AID - Serafino Romualdi (Box 5, Folder 9)
- AID - Shearer (Box 5, Folder 10)
- AID - Short-Term Staff Needs (Box 5, Folder 11)
- AID - Staff Regulations (Box 5, Folder 12)
- AID - State Department Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 13)
- AID - Translations (Box 5, Folder 14)
- AID - Correspondence w/ University of Chile (Box 5, Folder 15)
- AID - Chile Project Reports (Box 5, Folder 16)
- India Program (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Indian Program - Ford Foundation - New Delhi (Box 5, Folder 18)
- India Program - Leonard Adams (Box 5, Folder 19)
- India Program - Ford Foundation - New York City (Box 5, Folder 20)
- India Program - Institute of International Education (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Indian Program - Institute Documents (Box 5, Folder 22)
- India Program - Confidential Report (Box 5, Folder 23)
- India Program - Ralph James (Box 5, Folder 24)
- India Program - ST Merani (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Indian Program - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Indian Program - Personnel Pol. & Info. (Box 5, Folder 27)
- India Program - Shri Ram Centre (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Liberian Project (Box 6, Folder 1)
- International Labor Training (Box 6, Folder 2)
- ILTP Program Reports (Box 6, Folder 3)
- ILTP Correspondence & Memos, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- ILTP Correspondence & Memos, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- ILTP Marshall Foundation (Box 6, Folder 6)
- ILTP Foreign Trade Union Scholarships (Box 6, Folder 7)
- ILTP Reports on Internship Group I (Box 6, Folder 8)
- ILTP Reports on Internship Group II (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Middle East Program (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Puerto Rico (Box 6, Folder 11)
- PR Institute Development Program 1/2 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- PR Institute Development Program 2/2 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Puerto Rican Program in New York City (Box 6, Folder 14)
- PR LA Program - Miles Galvin, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- PR LA Program - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- PR LA Program - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- PR LA Program - Internal Memos (Box 6, Folder 18)
- PR LA Program - Marshall Foundation (Box 6, Folder 19)
- PR LA - Financial Reports (Box 6, Folder 20)
- PR LA Program - Budget Estimates 1/2 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- PR LA Program - Budget Estimates 2/2 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- PR LA Program - Activity Reports 1/2, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  June 1963-1964
- PR LA Program - Activity Reports 2/2, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- PR LA Program - Activity Reports 1/2, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  July 1960-1962
- PR LA Program - Activity Reports 2/2, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Training Program for Labor Educators Report (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Beichman, Arnold (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Commission for International Development (Box 7, Folder 2)
- U.S. Department of State (Special) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Lovestone, Jay, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Lovestone, Jay 1/2, 1950-1961 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Lovestone, Jay 2/2, 1950-1961 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Ahmad, Eqbal (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Conference: London Conference, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Fiszman, Joseph (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Frank, Beryl (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Fulbright Grant John Windmuller 1/2, 1952-1964 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Fulbright Grant John Windmuller 2/2, 1952-1964 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Miles Galvin, Uni. Of Puerto Rico (Box 7, Folder 13)
- ICFTU Congresses (Box 7, Folder 14)
- International Society for Labor Law & Social Legislation (Box 7, Folder 15)
- New Leader (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Political Science Quarterly (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Zofka, Borek (Box 7, Folder 18)